<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://example.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post #3 - Polling in America</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/blog-post-3-polling-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/blog-post-3-polling-in-america/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Throughout the 21st Century, political punditry and forecasing has been paramount to understanding our national, political environment. Forecasters have used a variety of methods to pinpoint and predict the outcome of future elections. With a significant, recent rise in data analysis, horserace polling, and punditry, election forecasting has risen in popularity as well. Websites such as FiveThirtyEight &amp;amp; the Economist have begun to publish reoccurring election forecasts, depending on the election year. Whether a midterm or presidential election, these sites provide predictions and estimations for both sides of aisle–-backed up by data and statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accurately predict an election, however, pundits rely heavily on public, non-partisan polls to fuel their predictions. Polls are typically regarded as the single, most important predictor in any election–at least until 2016. In 2016, the polls were significantly off, dramatically reducing trust in the polling industry. As we move into the 2022 midterm elections, the apprehension behind polls is still apparent, though recent sucesses in 2018 &amp;amp; 2020 have quelled some fears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, FiveThirtyEight is a forecasting company that churns out election forecasts in every midterm &amp;amp; presdiential election post-2010, ran by Nate Silver. In their model, they hold many factors to be important in their modeling: basic partisanship, errors found in race-to-race, likely voters, timeline adjustment, house effects adjustment, and present-day issues (such as COVID-19’s impact on voting). They weigh these models using different measures depending on what is most important and accurate within predicting. However, there are significant factors that guide FiveThirtyEight’s forecast towards the right and left wing. These are what we call “fundamentals.” Fundamentals are factors beyond polling that contribute to the race’s outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentals can include: an incumbent’s margin of victory in past elections, fundraising, 538’s partisan lean, congressional approval, scandals, voting record, and a challenger’s quality. These factors aide in the decision-making process in FiveThirtyEight’s model, with an emphasis on incumbency (+ performance) and generic ballot polling data. Additionally, FiveThirtyEight utilizes 3 different models for their predictions: Lite (polling + CANTOR), Classic (include fundamentals), Deluxe (include expert forecasts). They weigh their polls &amp;amp; adjust it based on time frame–providing a more accurate prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. Elliot Morris runs The Economist’s forecast for elections, relying heavily on their own fundamentals and indicators for their predictions. As we are focused on Congressional (House) elections for 2022, we will be looking at Morris &amp;amp; The Economist’s House Fundamentals: partisan voting history, campaign fundraising, and other factors, similar to FiveThirtyEight. Of course, they utilize the generic ballot as well for their overall indicators. The generic ballot is a shared trait through nearly all pundits and forecasters, as it is a considerable indicator of public support and sentiment towards both parties. We also find that The Economist uses district-level data as part of their fundamentals – FiveThirtyEight does something similar, but it we find both models are hyper-specific. As noted in their 2018 model, The Economist uses a Skew-T distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for predictions on the presidential level, The Economist uses economic data (GDP), presidential approval, and more. This data serves as The Economist’s “fundamentals,” as the coined term in FiveThirtyEight’s forecast. Overall, The Economist finds itself weighing similar to FiveThirtyEight (and other forecasters… see DecisionDeskHQ, RaceToTheWhiteHouse, etc.). Though, they have their differences when it comes to weighting and decision-making behind factors to include in their predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two, I would preference FiveThirtyEight over The Economist. While I do believe that both are relatively accurate forecasters, FiveThirtyEight seems to take into consideration more factors than The Economist. Just through a simple look through of their websites, FiveThirtyEight has more interactive portions of their model that provides the viewer a better understanding of their predictions. Additionally, I prefer the 3 levels of modelling to help compare &amp;amp; contrast predictions from Lite, Classic, and Deluxe. Having the different levels helps me understand the impact of solely polling, then fundamentals included, then finally, expert forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we will be utilizing a FiveThirtyEight strategy to understanding the impact of polling &amp;amp; the economy on the midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, we will explore the generic ballot final numbers in November and compare it to the actual results of the midterm election. For this blog post, we will be exploring “Incumbent Party Vote Share.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;generic-ballot-value-vs-actual-over-time&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Generic Ballot Value vs Actual Over Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-3-polling-in-america/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above graph, we find that there is a correlation between November polling data &amp;amp; final results for political parties. The question is… how strong is the correlation? To find this, we calculated the linear regression model of the relationship between incumbent president’s party vote &amp;amp; the incumbent president’s party polls in November, we find the R squared value to be 0.5843. This reveals we have a moderate relationship between the two variables, thus making the November polls a somewhat accurate predictor of the actual election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following our finding of this moderate relationship, we decided to predict the 2022 midterms based on the Democratic Party’s current numbers in the FiveThirtyEight generic ballot. To set up this prediction, we used the model that formed the above graph, and included a new data frame of the Democratic Party’s numbers as of right now. The current D Party vote share in the generic ballot is 45.3%, and thus, we will use that as our input to predict the actual Democratic Party vote share. When using the model &amp;amp; the new input, we find our prediction to put the Democrats at 49.42% for the 2022 vote-share. This is an under performance from their popular vote share from 2018 &amp;amp; 2020, which we can likely conclude results in a democratic loss in the House this November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we will look at the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;moving-onto-economic-impacts&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving onto Economic Impacts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-3-polling-in-america/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-4-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
To use economic data, I decided to use GDP growth in the 2nd quarter of the year, to help us better match where the 2022 midterms currently are. Based on the 2nd quarter GDP growth, we created a linear regression model of the relationship between that same GDP growth percentage &amp;amp; the incumbent president’s vote share. In addition to the linear regression model, we created a graph to show the relationship between the variables. In both the visual &amp;amp; calculated linear regression R^2 value, we found no correlation between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The R-squared value was -0.012, and thus, is actually predicting worse than a standard line. As a result, we likely cannot rely on GDP growth as a means of predicting the midterm elections, as it does us a disservice. However, for the sake of it, we will calculate the expectation for Democrats based on the 2022 Quarter 2’s GDP growth (-0.9%). With this number, the model predicts Democrats will have 48.02% of the vote share. The economy can serve as an equivalent to one of FiveThrityEight’s “fundamentals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will combine both factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;combined-economic-polling-model&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Combined Economic + Polling Model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-3-polling-in-america/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-5-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
After combining both factors, we found the strength to return to a moderate correlation. The R-squared value was found to be 0.57, but this is largely led by the relationship between polling and actual numbers, rather than GDP. Having less of an R-squared value with BOTH variables added in than with JUST polling likely indicates GDP growth was detrimental to my model. In this combined model, it found that the Democratic Party’s expected vote share is 49.37%, not too far off either of the other models. However, I have some difficulty trusting the combined model, as GDP growth is certainly not the best variable for predicting the midterms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, we have 3 main takeaways from this blog post:
1. Polls in November are pretty good at predicting the actual vote share in the election
2. GDP growth in quarter 2 isn’t good at predicting the actual vote share in the election
3. Democrats still likely lose the House based on all 3 of the models created&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we move forward, I am looking to change my economic variables to make the model more accurate, or consider entirely scrapping it from the final model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post #2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post #1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Question/Blog Extension we are going to be going through:
Heterogenous Predictive Power of the Economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does the effect of the economy vary when we consider popular vote versus seat share as our outcome (dependent) variable?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does the predictive power of economy change across time? If so, why?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, this blog post will be dealing with data sets that have been filtered and combined through R. This blog post will be utilizing GDP Quarter 7 data from the midterm years 1962-2018. By my own discretion, I have removed the presidential election years, as the data set does not treat the “president_party” variable as the party going into the election, but rather the victor of the presidential election. Consequently, I felt it would be most beneficial if that was taken out of the equation for this blog post. Additionally, as this class is focused on the 2022 midterms, I hoped to utilize the midterm-only data to guage a better understanding of midterms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sort our data, I combined economic data and House of Representatives election data. In addition, we filtered, then mutated the data to create two new variables within our blog: pres_party_seat_share and pres_party_vote_share. The seat share was defined as the # of seats for the president’s party divided by 435 (total # of seats in the U.S. House). This also explains the reasoning behind the year selection, beginning in 1960, as that was the first year in history with 435 House seats (following Hawaii &amp;amp; Alaska’s addition to the United States).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-5-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
With this data, we first created a scatterplot based on the “Quarter 7 GDP Growth” and “President’s Party Seat Share.” GDP growth in Quarter 7 was chosen as the most recent quarter leading into an election. The expectation was that a recent bump (or lackthereof) in the economy would either benefit/hinder the president’s party in seat share (similar to what we read in Healy and Lenz || &amp;amp; Achens). To test, we formed the scatterplot while placing a linear regression model line on the graph itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal expectations were that GDP growth would result in president’s party seat share being nearly 50% or above. Unfortunately, the model did not find the GDP growth and party seat share to follow my expectations. There were numerous instances where the president’s party’s seat share was below 50%, despite the GDP growth being around 1% or even more. Whenever the GDP growth was negative, the president’s party never received above 50% of the seat share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-6-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Then, we moved on to see if the president’s party’s vote share was more reflective than seat share, as described by the blog extension. When we ran the model, we did not find it to be particularly accurate, but there were instances (similar to seat share) of accuracy. Again, the economy and seat share relationship did not match expectations to the extent that was originally thought. Though similar to the president’s party seat share, it did reveal that there was not one instance where a president’s party won the majority of the popular vote when GDP growth was negative. This made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we aimed to calculate the actual linear regression number on the GDP growth pct as it relates to president’s party vote vote share &amp;amp; president’s party seat share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-7-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
To begin, we looked at the relationship at a quantified relationship between pres_party_vote_share and GDP_growth_pct. We found the calculation to be 3.65, thus indicating that for every 1% increase in GDP, we can expect the president’s party vote share to increase by 3.65%. I do think this number could be defending in traditional election circumstances, but the 15 midterm years we are utilizing for analysis make me somewhat uncertain about this. If I had the ability, I would use data from past midterms well beyond 1962, given that I had additional time &amp;amp; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-8-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
We then ran the other calculation. Our calculations found a value of 8.174 between a lm calculation of pres_party_seat_share and GDP_growth_pct. This means that for every 1% increase in GDP, we could expect an 8.17% increase in pres party’s seat share. However, I do not buy this number. This is such a large number that simply does not make much sense in the modern political world. A 1% increase will likely not result in an 8% increase in future elections, especially midterm ones with many more factors than the economy. While an interesting finding, I do not know if I trust it entirely. Similar to above, I would also wish to explore this with additional time &amp;amp; resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-9-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-9-2.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-10-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/blog-post-1/index.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-10-2.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
The second part of this blog extension is to see if there is a change in accuracy over time in these elections. Plainly put: there does not appear to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine this, we utilized a plot that mapped both a predicted model (based on our data) and the actual model. The party vote share based on actual results vs predicted results did find some spot-on accuracies in the elections of: 1974, 1982, 1990, and 2008. There were also some close calls, but on the overall, it was not nearly as predicitive as it could’ve been. Given the range of accuracy/innacuracies across the time frame, I believe that there is not a significant difference overtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When applying this to seat share, predicted vs actual, there were spot on predictions but also many that missed the mark. Generally, there were not many points of consistent accuracy or consistent inaccuracies, as accuracy was a variety across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main takeaways:
GDP growth does not seem to be the most predicitve/accurate indicator for a president’s seat growth or vote share
“It’s the economy, stupid.” may not be as true as we think
Time did not help the accuracy/predictive ability of our models&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources:
1. Achen and Bartels (2017)
2. Healy and Lenz (2014)
3. I did not use Wright as there was no unemployment calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data being used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;GDP growth (national): 1947-2022 (US Bureau of Economic Analysis, Department of Commerce)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Real disposable income (national): 1959-2022 (US Bureau of Economic Analysis)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation – CPI (national): 1947-2022 (US Bureau of Labor Statistics, Department of Labor)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unemployment (national): 1948-2022 (US Bureau of Labor Statistics)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unemployment (state): 1976-2022 (US Bureau of Labor Statistics)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://example.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Project</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
